

Web Developer

http://samliu.me

Phone: +61 434390783 Email: sliu178@gmail.com Skype: sam-cblock

## **OBJECTIVE**

I am seeking a creative and challenging position in web development that utilize my skills and further expand my technical skills.

#### SUMMARY

A well rounded web developer with over five years of experience in analyzing, developing and managing websites and web applications. Constantly learning and self-directed with the ability to work independently and as part of a team.

My ability to research, analyze and solve problems with a great instinct, determination and business sense can be an instant benefit to your team or organization.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: PHP, Python, Javascript, Objective C, HTML,

OOP, Design pattern

Database: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Technologies & Tools: memcache, Codelgniter, Django, jQuery, smarty

Operating Systems: CentOS, FreeBSD, Windows, Mac OS

Web servers: Apache, lighttpd, nginx Data Mining: google analytic, kontagent

Version Control: Git, Mercurial

## LANGUAGES

Fluent in English and Mandarin Chinese.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelancer, Saturday LLC., Taipei, Taiwan — 2011~recent

Audio-Technica Taiwan (<a href="http://www.audio-technica.com.tw/">http://www.audio-technica.com.tw/</a>)
 Redesigned and developed website using PHP, MySQL.Javascript, jQuery.

Phone: +61 434390783 Email: sliu178@gmail.com Skype: sam-cblock

- Jellybird Company (<a href="http://www.jellybirdcompany.com/">http://www.jellybirdcompany.com/</a>)
  Developed website using Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, Javascript, jQuery.
- Tarot Yearcycle (<a href="http://itunes.apple.com/tw/app/ta-luo-liu-nian/id477137482?mt=8">http://itunes.apple.com/tw/app/ta-luo-liu-nian/id477137482?mt=8</a>)
  Developed iOS application for apple app store

#### Software Developer, meeya Inc., Taipei, Taiwan — 2008~2011

- Developed "social group" (similar to facebook's page) function for social website meeya.cc
- Developed a PHP, MySQL based web game called "island7" for social website meeya.cc
- Developed facebook social application solutions using PHP,Python Django, MySQL for internet marketing campaigns.
- Lead backend developer for facebook social game "StoreCity" using PHP, MySQL and MongoDB database using AMFPHP to communicate with flash game client.
- Lead developer for social game "StoreCity" cross platform deployment. Deployed on mixi japan, mobage japan, Hyves Nederlands and Nasza Klasa Poland using OpenSocial protocol.

# Software Developer, CoreLight Technology Co., Ltd., Taipei, Taiwan — 2007~2008

- Maintained, Bug fixed and added features to the LMS(Learning management system) platform(built using PHP).
- Implemented blog system & live broadcast channel into Shih Chien University Library website using PHP and MySQL on windows NT.

### **EDUCATION**

University of Auckland, New Zealand — BSc, Computer Science 2001~2003

#### OTHER

- · Participant of Yahoo! Open Hack Day Taiwan 2008
- · Volunteer helper for Facebook Developer Garage Taipei 2009,2010